Sitwell, Osbert, 1892-1969. Osbert Sitwell correspondence and compositions, 1950-1967 (MS Eng 1293): Guide.
Osbert Sitwell correspondence and compositions,
1950-1967.
Houghton Library, Harvard College Library, Harvard University
MS Eng 1293
Sitwell, Osbert, 1892-1969.
2 boxes (1 linear ft.)
Contains correspondence of English authors Osbert and Edith Sitwell from friends in their literary, artistic, and social world as well as compositions by them.
72M-46. Gift of Mr. Frederick R. Koch, 101 West 12th. Street New York, New York 10011; received: 1973 March 29.
There are no restrictions on physical access to this material.
Sitwell was an English author.
Organized into the following series:
I. Letters to Edith Sitwell
II. Letters to Sir Osbert Sitwell
III. Other letters
IV. Compositions
Contains letters written to Osbert Sitwell, his sister Edith, and to other Sitwell family members. Letters mention Edith's poetry anthology book, a disrespectful article about Edith in the journal Isis, questions and thoughts about the poetry collection The Creative Encounter, and a description of the Quaker College Haverford in Pennsylvania. Also contains many letters from Baroness Christabel Aberconway to Edith concerning travels in Russia and Paris, meeting with Ambassadors in London, and a trip on the ship S.S. United States. Osbert received letters from Lorna Andrade who was managing business while he was away in Florence and also wrote him about current art shows. Letters also express sympathy for the death of Edith, life in New York city, and the Vietnam war. There is also a letter recommending Osbert for Commander of the Order of the British Empire. Also include two letters from Gore Vidal concerning the death of Edith, letters from Osbert's brother Sacheverell, and a letter from James Whittaker asking for a letter on his behalf for knighthood.
- I. Letters to Edith Sitwell
  Letters to Edith Sitwell from various correspondents.
  - Brittain-Catlin, John. 2 letters; 1950 [n.d.]., (1)
    No. 2 lacks beginning.
  - Day-Lewis, Cecil, 1904- 1 letter; [n.d.]., (2)
  - Dickson, Lovat, 1902- 1 letter; 1950., (3)
  - Guinness, Sir Alec, 1914- 1 letter; 1956., (4)
  - Nichols, Beverley, 1899- 1 letter; [n.d.]., (5)
  - Senhouse, Roger. 1 letter; 1959., (6)
  - Snow, Pamela. 1 letter; 1959., (7)
- II. Letters to Sir Osbert Sitwell
  Letters to Sir Osbert Sitwell from various correspondents.
  - Aberconway, Christobel Mary Melville (Macnaghten) McLaren, baroness, 1890- 16 letters; 1955-1966., (8)
  - Acton, Harold Mario Mitchell, 1904- 4 letters; 1965., (9)
  - Andrade, Lorna. 29 letters; 1955-1968 [n.d.]., (10)
    No. 29 lacks beginning.
  - Ashton, Frederick, 1904- 1 letter; [n.d.]., (11)
  - Butler, Renya. 2 letters; 1964-1966., (12)
  - Codyre, Patrick. 3 letters; 1960-1967., (13)
  - Gielgud, John, 1904- 1 letter; [n.d.]., (14)
  - Greenlees, Ian. 1 letter; 1966., (15)
  - Guinness, Sir Alec, 1914- 1 letter; 1959., (16)
  - Huxley, Sir Julian Sorell, 1887- 1 letter; 1956., (17)
  - Kirstein, Lincoln, 1907- 1 letter; 1959., (18)
  - Laurence, Desmond Roger. 16 letters; 1955-1966 [n.d.]., (19)
    No. 16 lacks beginning.
  - Lytton, Noel Anthony Scawen Lytton, 4th earl of, 1900- 1 letter; 1955., (20)
  - MacMillan, Harold, 1894- 1 letter; 1955., (21)
    Written by a secretary.
  - Masefield, John, 1878-1967. 1 letter; 1959., (22)
  - Moore, Henry Spencer, 1898- 1 letter; 1966., (23)
  - Moore, Marianne, 1887-1972. 3 letters; 1954-1965., (24)
  - Newnham, Henry. 10 letters; 1956-1966 [n.d.]., (25)
  - Nugent, Tim. 1 letter; 1956., (26)
  - O'Shaughnessy, Michael, 1912- 1 letter; [n.d.]., (27)
  - Pacini, Piero. 1 letter; 1966., (28)
  - Painter, George Duncan, 1914- 1 letter; 1965., (29)
  - Pierpont Morgan Library, New York. 1 letter; 1967., (30)
  - Plomer, William, 1903- 9 letters; 1956-1965., (31)
  - Powell, Anthony D. 1 letter; 1956., (32)
  - Rizzoli, Arturo. 1 letter; 1956., (33)
  - Ruck, Berta, 1878- 2 letters; 1956-1966., (34)
  - Sackville-West, Victoria, 1892- 1 letter; 1958., (35)
  - Severini, Jeanne. 1 letter; 1966., (36)
  - Sieveking, Lancelot de Giberne, 1896- 1 letter; 1955., (37)
  - Sitwell, Reresby, 1927- 2 letters; 1966 [n.d.]., (38)
  - Sitwell, Sacheverell, 1897- 19 letters; 1955-1966 [n.d.]., (39)
  - Snow, Pamela. 1 letter; 1959., (40)
  - Vidal, Gore, 1925- 2 letters; 1965 [n.d.]., (41)
  - Waley, Arthur, 1889- 2 letters; [n.d.]., (42)
  - Whittaker, James. 8 letters; 1955-1956 [n.d.]., (43)
    Nos. 6-8 are incomplete.
  - Wilkinson, R. F. 1 letter (copy); 1955., (44)
  - Wilson, Sandy, 1924- 1 letter; 1958., (45)
- III. Other letters
  - Acton, Harold Mario Mitchell, 1904- 1 letter to Christobel Mary Melville (Macnaghten) McLaren Aberconway; 1965., (46)
  - Sitwell, Edith, 1887-1964. 1 letter to the Spectator; 1950., (47)
    2 drafts.
  - Sitwell, Edith, 1887-1964. 1 letter to Feliks Topolski; 1959., (48)
    Incomplete draft.
  - Sitwell, Edith, 1887-1964. 1 letter to []; [n.d.]., (49)
    Incomplete.
  - Sitwell, Edith, 1887-1964. 1 letter to []; [n.d.]., (50)
  - Sitwell, Erik. 1 letter to Sir George Reresby Sitwell; 1935., (51)
  - Sitwell, Sir George Reresby, bart., 1860-1943. 1 letter to Florence Alice Sitwell; 1921., (52)
  - Sitwell, Lady Louisa. 4 letters to Sir George Reresby Sitwell; 1853-1857 [n.d.]., (53)
    No. 4 lacks beginning.
  - Sitwell, Sir Osbert, bart., 1892-1969. 1 letter to Noel Anthony Scawen Lytton, 4th earl of Lytton; 1955., (54)
    With a draft.
  - Thomas, F G F 1 letter to Sir George Reresby Sitwell; 1929., (55)
  - Wilton, Richard, 1827-1903. 1 letter to Richard Cecil Wilton; 1886., (56)
  - Wilton, Richard Cecil, 1864-1948. 1 letter to Sir George Reresby Sitwell; 1925., (57)
  - [Letters from unidentified persons], (58); 1 folder.
- IV. Compositions
  - Sitwell, Edith, 1887-1964. Preface. A.MS.s.; [n.p.,n.d.], (59); 1s. (1p.).
    Unidentified fragment.
  - Sitwell, Edith, 1887-1964. [Will] TS. (photocopy); Renishaw, 10 Dec 1956., (60); 5s. (5p.).
  - Sitwell, Sir George Reresby, bart., 1860-1943. [Miscellaneous A.MS. fragments]; [n.p.] Apr 1928 [n.d.]., (61); 3s. (6p.).
  - Sitwell, Lady Ida. Notes from Mrs. Sitwell. TS. (fragment); [n.p.,n.d.], (62); 2s. (2p.).
  - Sitwell, Sir Osbert, bart., 1892-1969. Leonora. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p.,n.d.], (63); 5s. (6p.).
    Working draft of a poem.
  - Sitwell, Sir Osbert, bart., 1892-1969. [Unidentified poetic fragment]. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p.,n.d.], (64); 1s. (2p.).
  - Miscellaneous, (65); 4 folders.